A Guide to the Letters of Upton Sinclair to John Moore, 1931-1964
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters from Upton Sinclair to John Moore, 1931-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6777-n
This collection consists of 14 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from David G. Holmes on 22 August 1997.
Scope and Content Information
Upton Sinclair, Pasedena and Monrovia, California, to John Moore, in response to Moore's inquiries throughout the years. Many concern meetings with Moore and Moore's requests for publishing help. Other topics include the physical versus the spiritual realm; Sinclair's play Love in Arms and a novel on California cooperatives; government suppression of communism, pacifism and anarchism; financial aid for poets; and the re-election of Roosevelt in 1936.
Contents List
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 11 July 1931, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, makes arrangements to meet for lunch at the Young Women's Christian Association in Pasadena.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 21 July 1931, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, expresses pleasure at meeting him and offers to send him some books discussing the questions he has asked.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 24 August 1931, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, comments on the two realms in human affairs, "the physical which includes the economic, and the spiritual. Some day I hope we may all be able to live in the spiritual realm. In the meantime, until we get our economic problems settled, we certainly have to criticize each other, and deal very strenuously with injustice in that field."
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 3 October 1931, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, thanks him for his letters and the opportunity to reread about Tom Moore's visit to America.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 29 July 1932, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, offers to recommend Moore's manuscript to several publishers he knows but cannot do more because he is buried in his own work.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 10 Auguts 1932, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, tells Moore that he cannot help him further because of the press of his own work; Sinclair is finishing a book which involves an immense amount of research and is starting to write a play.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 21 October 1934, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Los Angeles, California, cannot spare time for another visit as he is "so swamped with the work of the campaign that it is utterly impossible for me to make any engagements that do not bear directly upon that work."
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 12 March 1936, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California, sends a copy of his play, Love In Arms, desiring Moore's reaction and tells Moore he knows no details about the Fascists.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 24 March 1936, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California, thinks there was a review of Love In Arms, in the Pasadena Star-News when it was produced but does not know of anything else that was published.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 8 April 1936, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California, wishes him success with his article, but tells him, "Forgive me if I explain to you that I am completely absorbed in the novel I am writing dealing with our California co-operatives, and I try to avoid every kind of engagement which takes my mind off that job"; on the verso of the letter are some notes comparing the persecution of the early Christians by the Roman government to the modern attempts of government to stamp out communism, pacifism, or anarchism.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 27 May 1936, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California [discusses help for poets, "Thirty-three years ago I was calling for financial help for poets in my book, The Journal of Arthur Stirling, and now I am very glad to see it being attempted."; on the verso of the letter are some comments about the election of President Franklin D. Roosevelt.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 30 March 1937, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California, writes again that he does not have any time to read the manuscripts of others.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 8 January 1938, TLS, 1 page.
  Upton Sinclair, Pasadena, California, to John Moore, Hollywood, California, returns Moore's article on poetry which he has read.
- Upton Sinclair to John Moore 2[9] March 1964, TLS, 1 page, with envelope.
  Upton Sinclair, Monrovia, California, to John Moore, Pasadena, California, answers his question about a play produced five years ago off Broadway, New York City, and advises that translations of Catullus should be available in the Pasadena or Los Angeles Libraries.